A Guide to the McGeary Campaign Literature Collection, 1951-2010
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
McGeary Campaign Literature Collection, 1951-2010
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
RG 186
4 boxes.
McGeary, Scott
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Scott McGeary in June 2011.
Scope and Content
RG 186 houses Scott McGeary's personal collection of political materials for Arlington County and Virginia. The record group measures approximately two linear feet and dates from 1951 to 2010 (bulk 1960-2002). Types of material include printed campaign literature, sample ballots, photographs, clippings, and a thesis. While most of the materials are for the Republican or Democratic parties, there are also some nonpartisan materials, including a thesis on Arlingtonians for a Better County by Franklin O. Felt. Materials cover the two major parties for most years for elections in local, state, and Congressional races.
Candidate qualifications stressed in the materials include understanding of local and state conditions, personal probity, high levels of education, and depth of experience, especially at the local level. Many candidates for state positions served first on the Arlington School Board, then on the Arlington County Board. Matters of policy most mentioned are fiscal responsibility (i.e. low taxes), education funding, and transportation issues. The tone of the materials is uniformly civil, reflecting a courteous and positive rather than an aggressive campaign style and presenting a candidate's virtues rather than emphasizing an opponent's defects.
Arrangement
Record Group 186 maintains the original organization and arrangement created by Mr. McGeary. There are four series by type of material: loose campaign materials, sample ballots (both in chronological order), a thesis about Arlingtonians for a Better County, and individual Arlington and Virginia officials and candidates campaign materials, removed from loose-leaf binders to file folders, but still kept in alphabetical order. Folders containing photographs have an asterisk [*] after the file name. Folders with oversized materials have a double asterisk [**] to denote where material was removed and separation sheets added.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Researchers interested in partisan politics in Arlington and Virginia may consult records such as RG 26, Campaign Literature, or RG 137, Records of the Arlington County Democratic Committee. For individual candidates see, for example, RG 65, the Personal Papers of Mary A. Marshall, RG 108, Personal Papers of Roye Lowry, or RG 168, the Personal Papers of Mary Margaret Whipple. RG 94 contains Arlingtonians for a Better County Organizational Records.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Women -- United States.; Arlington County (Va.) -- Politics and government.; Virginia -- Politics and government.
Contents List
- Loose Campaign Materials
  - Republican Candidate Literature, 1951 (Box 1)
  - AIM Candidate Literature: Leone Buchholz, 1954 (Box 1)
  - AIM Candidate Literature, 1955 (Box 1)
  - AIM Candidate Literature, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Democratic Candidate Primary Literature: Kathryn Stone, 1957 (Box 1)
  - AIM Candidate Literature: Leone Buchholz, 1958 (Box 1)
  - "Ike" Bumper Sticker, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Republican Candidate Campaign Materials, 1961 (Box 1)
  - ABC Candidate Campaign Materials: Roye Lowry, 1961 (Box 1)
  - DCYR Candidate Literature, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Arlington Republican Party Joint Materials, 1961 (Box 1)
  - ABC Candidate Literature: Leo Urbanske, Jr., 1962 (Box 1)
  - Democratic Candidate Literature: Allen Harrison, 1962 (Box 1)
  - ABC Candidate Literature, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Republican Candidate Literature, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Guy Farley Literature, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Republican Candidate Literature: Richard May, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Republican Candidate Literature, 1965 (Box 1)
  - ABC Candidate Literature: Roye Lowry, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Democratic Candidate Literature: Clive DuVal, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Campaign Literature, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Republican State Convention Candidate Literature: Kenneth Haggerty, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Joint Independent Literature, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Perot Literature, 1992 (Box 1)
  - County Board Special Election Literature, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Individual Literature, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Arlington County School Board Literature, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Arlington County Board Democratic Primary Candidate Literature (Partial), 1995 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Republican Candidate Literature, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Arlington County Board Special Election Campaign Literature, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Arlington School Board Candidate Literature, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Arlington County Republican Party Canvass for Arlington County Board, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Republican Primary Literature for Lt. Governor and Attorney General, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Democratic Primary for 48th House of Delegates District Seat & Arlington County Board, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Arlington County Special Election for Arlington County Board Literature, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Arlington County Public School Bond Issue Literature, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Arlington County Special Election for County Board Democratic Literature, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Arlington County School Board Candidate Literature, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature (some Fairfax County), 1999 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature and Endorsed School Board Candidate, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Independent Candidate for County Board Endorsed by County Republicans, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Joint Democratic Literature, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Joint Republican Literature, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Democratic Literature, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Independent School Board Literature, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Special Election for Arlington County Board Republican Candidate Literature, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Special Election for Arlington County Board Democratic Candidate Literature, 2003 (Box 2)
- Sample Ballots
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1965 (Box 2)
  - ABC Sample Ballot, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Independent Sample Ballot, 1975 (Box 2)
  - ABC Sample Ballot, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Independent Sample Ballot, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Independent Sample Ballot, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Independent Sample Ballot, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Independent Sample Ballot, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Republican Presidential Primary Sample Ballot, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Bond Issue Sample Ballot, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Bond Issue Sample Ballot, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Perot Sample Ballot, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Bonds Sample Ballot, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Arlington County General Election Ballot, 1995 ** (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Special Election Democratic Sample Ballot, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Arlington County Electoral Board, 2001 ** (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Firefighters and Police Officers Sample Ballot, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Arlington County Electoral Board Sample Ballot, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Republican Sample Ballot, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Democratic Sample Ballot, 2002 (Box 2)
- Arlington and Virginia Officials and Candidates Campaign Materials
  - Abbit, W. M., [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Arthur, Beth, 1999-[2000] (Box 2)
  - Baber, John, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Barr, John, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Beale, Herald "Skip," 1977 (Box 2)
  - Bell, David, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Beyer, Don, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Bolling, Bill, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Bozman, Ellen, [n.d.]* (Box 2)
  - Broyhill, Joel T., 1952-1974 (Box 2)
  - Brunner, Mike, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Byrd, Harry, Jr., 1970-1982 (Box 2)
  - Callahan, Vince, 1970 * (Box 2)
  - Calhoun, Robert L., 1984-1995 (Box 2)
  - Campbell, Edmund D. & Elizabeth P., 1952 1955-2009 (Box 2)
  - Coleman, Marshall, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Cuccinelli, Ken, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Dalton, Eddy, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Dalton, John, [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Darner, Karen, [1995] (Box 3)
  - Detwiler, Steve, 1978-1982 (Box 3)
  - Diamonstein, Alan, [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Dolan, Bill, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Durrette, Wyatt, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Earley, Mark, [2001] (Box 3)
  - Echols, Pat, [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Eisenberg, Albert C., 1990 (Box 3)
  - Fahey, Helen, [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Faust, Tom, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Ferguson, Paul, [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Fisette, Jay, [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Foster, David M., [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Frankland, Walter L., 1983 (Box 3)
  - Gilmore, Jim, [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Gondles, Jim, 1979-1986 (Box 3)
  - Green, George Mason, Jr., [1971?] (Box 3)
  - Hager, John, 1987-1997 (Box 3)
  - Haggerty, Kenneth M., 1964-1969 (Box 3)
  - Hassan, William, 1962 * (Box 3)
  - Holland, Edward M., 1971 * (Box 3)
  - Holton, Linwood, 1969-1978 (Box 3)
  - Hudson, Henry E., 1979-1983 (Box 3)
  - Hunter, James B., 1990-1998 * (Box 3)
  - Hynes, Mary, [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Kaine, Timothy M., 2006 (Box 3)
  - Kelly, Mark, [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Kilgore, Jerry, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Lechner, Ira, [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - McAuliffe, Terry, 2009 (Box 3)
  - McDonnell, Robert, [2005]-2010 (Box 3)
  - McGeary, Scott, [n.d.]* (Box 3)
  - Mann, C. Harrison, 1976-1977 * (Box 3)
  - Marshall, John, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Melnik, John, [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Miller, Clint, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Milliken, John, [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Mitchell, Conchita, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Moran, James, [n.d.]* (Box 3)
  - Morgan, Herbert, 1972 -[n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Newman, Bill, 1987 (Box 3)
  - O'Leary, Frank, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Obenshain, Richard D., [1978] (Box 3)
  - Parris, Stan, [n.d.]* (Box 3)
  - Pascoe, Bill, [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Robertson, A. Willis, [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Robinson, J. Kenneth, [n.d.]* (Box 3)
  - Saslaw, Richard L., [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Sawfield, David, [n.d.]* (Box 3)
  - Shafran, Tom, [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Spong, William B., [1966] (Box 3)
  - Stambaugh, Warren, [1985]-1990 (Box 3)
  - Steinmetz, Michael, [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Trible, Paul, [1982]-1989 (Box 3)
  - Vasapoli, Joe, [n.d.]* (Box 3)
  - Wampler, William C., [n.d.]* (Box 3)
  - Warner, John, 1978, 2001, [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Warner, Mark, 2002 (Box 3)
  - West, Jade, [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - Whipple, Mary Margaret, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Whitehurst, William, [n.d.]* (Box 3)
  - Wholey, Joe, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Wolf, Frank, 1975-1986 * (Box 4)
- Thesis, "A Study of a Nonpolitical Organization: The Arlingtonians For a Better County (ABC)" by Franklin O. Felt
  - Title Page - Page 135 (Box 4)
  - Page 136-257 (Box 4)